Hello everyone, this video is mainly for those who are not familiar with the use of Claw for 2D plating, or those who want to improve the knowledge of 2D plating in Claw.
I hope this video can help you better use 2D tools.
You can see the size table in the picture.
It is the US standard size ASTM MISSEY SIZE 10.
First, I will insert a virtual model into the plating window.
Then change its size and size table in SIZE.
In today's process, I will make the top coat first.
Then the hem.
The hem has chest hem, waist hem and shoulder hem.
Then the sleeve.
For the fabric, I use the crotch fabric in the plating window.
Let's start now.
You can see that the unit of this size table is inches.
First, we can go to the user self-definition of the settings.
The user interface above will change all units to inches.
Then click close.
This operation needs to restart the software to be able to update our newly set units.
Next, we come to the avatar of the plating window.
Then we choose Feifei.
Now you can see this is a default.
This is a default.
This is the size.
Then we come to the SIZE information box.
Click US ASTM MISSEY CURVY.
Then we choose size 10.
Now you can see that the size of the virtual model has been updated.
Then for the fabric part, we come to the fabric in the plating window.
We enter muslin in the search bar.
Then we use this muslin of 22x22.
Then we go to the object window.
First, we will switch the interface to full 2D display.
Because our top and bottom are left and right symmetrical.
So we see that the size table is one-third of the size of the right-hand side blue.
Then we first create a rectangle.
The widest is the chest width.
The longest is the back middle length.
The width is 9x17 inches.
Then now we use the internal line diameter to mark the width.
Then the width.
Then the length.
The back width is 6.625 inches.
We see the blue line 2, input 6.625.
Next is the front middle width.
The front middle width is 6.25 inches.
The middle width is 8.875.
The waist width is 6.875.
Now that all the dimensions are set, we can switch to the built-in multilinear line tool, the shortcut G.
Then we will draw its outline.
We can go from the back length to the shoulder height, and then to the sleeve length.
Then the last is the bottom line.
Draw a straight line.
Then again, we draw the front part.
We draw the front part.
We only need to draw the collar and the sleeve length.
The rest is the same as the back.
Now we can switch to the built-in multilinear tool.
Its shortcut is C.
We will make the back and the front into a multilinear.
Then we can use the built-in curve tool.
The shortcut is V.
The back and the front are based on the front center.
Make a 90 degree vertical.
Then on the sleeve, we use the multilinear tool to make it into a傾ề.
Now, we use the multilinear tool.
Its shortcut is I.
First, select the back piece, select the outline, and click the right button to select the back piece.
Then we can get the shape of the back piece.
Next, repeat the same operation, we do the front piece.
First select the outline of the front piece, then click the right button to select the back piece.
After selecting the front piece, we turn the front piece horizontally.
Then we organize the back piece.
We can use the edit tool to delete the extra points.
And delete the extra lines.
Only keep the front width, back width, and width of the front and back.
And we delete the extra points.
And we delete the extra lines.
Now I will make an inverse of this basic version.
Then I show the inner line.
We see a bigger model's size from the side.
In order to avoid the side hole going forward, we can move the side hole back by 0.375 inches.
Then select the side hole.
Click the Shift.
We enter 0.375 inches in the gap between the back and the center of the back, and the side of the back piece is corresponding to the center of the back, 0.375 inches.
Now we are going to move the back width to the center 1.8 inches, and move the bottom to the left 1.4 inches.
When I choose the inner line of the back width, I found that it has no focal point with the side of the back piece.
So I choose this point, right click, add point to the side of the board, and repeat the same operation on the middle line.
In this way, when we select this line and move it, it can be moved along with the outer line of the board.
Then we can see that the back center line after we move is very stiff.
So at this time, we will use the shortcut C to edit it a little more smoothly.
In the size table, the shoulder line goes forward 0.5 inches.
Then we select the shoulder line in the front, right click, and enter 0.5 inches.
Then we select the inner line, right click, and cut.
At this time, we select the edge of the board to cut, and then select the shoulder line in the back, and merge.
In this way, we have done the shoulder line part.
Then we can see that the edge of this merged line has two points, and it is indicated by a virtual line.
This line is our original shoulder line.
Then we can select these two points.
Then we can change it to a curve point to avoid interference caused by the modification of the board shape.
Now we start to do the line path.
Make a cut on the outer line of our board.
We can select the plus point division tool X.
The position of the middle line is 2 inches from the upper and lower sides of the shoulder line.
Next, we switch to the editor board tool Z.
Right click, add line.
We enter 1 on the width of 1.2.
Then the length of the joint is 4.5 inches.
When we click to confirm, there is a curve and a curve point.
This can allow us to adjust the edge curve after collecting the rope again.
This operation can ensure that the edge after collecting the rope is smooth.
Now I align all these curve points as a straight line.
This can ensure that our side seam is straight.
After adjusting, click the return key to complete the production of the rope path.
Now after collecting the rope.
The side seam of the front piece is finished.
The side seam of the back piece is 2 inches.
In order to ensure that it and the side seam of the back piece can be parallel,
I added 1 inch at the front of the shoulder line and the bottom of the shoulder line.
First, I click on the point of the shoulder line.
Press Shift to drag up and right-click.
I will enter the distance as 1 inch in the spring that appears.
Then in the bottom of the shoulder line, I directly select the whole line and drag up and down.
In this way, we can ensure that the side seam of the front piece and the back piece are equal in length.
Now we add the waist line.
We can see the size table.
The front waist line is 3 inches away from the center of the front.
The depth of the waist line is 1 in 2, which is 0.5.
At this time, we will use the plus point division tool to add a 3.5-inch section.
Then I use the edit version tool, the shortcut key Z.
Right-click on this section and add a line.
In the spring that appears, we will enter the width of 1 in 2 as 0.5.
Enter the length of the line as 5 and click OK.
Similarly, we will make this curve point a straight line.
Let's make a adjustment to this curve point.
After adjustment, press the reverse key.
In this way, our waist line is done.
We can re-examine the waist width.
First, click on all the bottom 100.
Then we see that the waist width is 11.954 inches.
The waist width in the scale table is 13.75.
I can right-click on the number on the example table.
Click on the calculator to calculate the difference between the two.
Then we can see that the difference between the two is 1.796 inches.
Let's divide this number by 2.
We get 0.898 inches.
I choose the point in the front.
Press Shift and drag it to the right.
Enter the movement distance.
Click OK.
Then come to the back.
The same operation.
Next, we will add the shoulder line.
First, I use the plus point line tool.
Right-click on the back.
In the south window, we choose the last one.
Average segment.
The number of lines is 2.
Then we can make the back line a equal.
Next, we use the edit sheet tool.
Right-click on this point.
Add a line.
The width of 1.25 is 0.25.
The length of the line is 4 inches.
Click OK.
Then we see that the waist width is 0.25.
Then we can add the shoulder line.
We can add a line.
Then we can add a line.
Add a line.
Then click OK.
The same step.
Adjusted the only line.
Adjusting the only line.
After refreshing, click the rewind button.
Now the shoulder line is finished.
Now we have removed the 0.5 inches from the back shoulder line.
Now it is fine.
Augment the shoulder line.
At the point near the sleeve ball,
like this.
Use the edit sheet tool.
Use the Ctrl icon.
Click insert there.
Please remember not to use the left button.
Drag it to the area.
We can make this point an extension on the line
Then click the mouse right button
We enter 0.5 inches in the spring that appears
In this way, we have completed all the
Next, we are going to check our audio on the virtual model
Use the edit panel tool to select the front and back panels
And right-click on the panel
Select the symmetrical panel
The panel is very realistic
The shortcut key is ctrl d
Then press shift before
So that we can lay out the panels in a horizontal way
Click on the center of the two front panels
Press shift to select more
Then right-click and click merge
We merge the front and center
After merging, we can make a adjustment to the point where the front and center are down
Here I can adjust the placement of our 2D panel in accordance with personal habits
Then we can arrange the panel on the virtual model
First, select the panel
Move the panel up
Show the virtual model
Select the panel
Then open the arrangement point
The shortcut key to the arrangement point is shift plus f
Click on the panel
Then click on the arrangement point
Then we can arrange the panel to the virtual model
This is a relatively simple style
So we can use the automatic sewing tool here
Click on the automatic sewing tool
In the pop-up box, the clothing type is the top
The advanced type, we choose 5
Then click OK
We can check the sewing line of the system
No problem
Open the simulation
Now move to the test angle of the model
We found that the dress balance has the situation of the front and the back
We can long press the circular measurement tool in the 3D window
Select the surface length measurement virtual model tool
We first draw its shoulder line on the virtual model
Next, we long press the edit measurement tool
Select the virtual model measurement
Then we choose the dress line
Then click on the model line we just drew
After opening the simulation
The dress line will be attached to the line we just drew
We drag the dress shape
Then move to the side of the dress
We found that the bottom is in a flat state
We change the fabric to a translucent surface in the circular menu of the 3D window
We can see that the seam allowance is too high
And the seam allowance is too long
Come to the 3D window
I move the seam allowance down to 0.5 inches
But after we adjust the seam allowance down
We found that the two sides of the seam are not equal
So now we choose the two sides of the seam allowance
Choose more at the same time
Then press the right button to select the adjustment seam
At this time, the curve with the red curve point will reappear
Then we adjust it again
After adjustment, click OK
This completes the adjustment of the seam allowance
The seam allowance after the adjustment is 5.257 inches
We will calculate it with the size table
Now this seam allowance is 0.757 inches
At this time, we choose the seam allowance point again
Press and hold the right mouse button
Enter the movement distance in the spring of the spring
Click OK
Re-model to see the seam allowance
Then we change the fabric to the fabric surface
At the side seam, because it is not vertical now
So when it is connected, it has a corner
Now we choose the two bottom points of the side seam
Drag down
Enter 0.25 inches in the spring of the spring
Click OK
Re-model to see the seam allowance effect
And then click OK
The seam allowance is now green
At this time, we choose the seam allowance point
Press and hold the right mouse button
Enter 0.25 inches in the spring of the spring
Click OK
Re-model to see the seam allowance effect
At this time, we choose the seam allowance point
Enter 0.25 inches in the spring of the spring
Click OK
Let's re-arrange the bottom line of the bottom line.
Next, let's check the adhesion of the outside of the board.
And add some sewing marks.
To check the connection between the front and back pieces of the circle.
We can use the copy function.
First, we use the edit board tool.
Select the front and back pieces of the front and back pieces.
And click the right button to copy.
The board will be arranged as shown on the screen.
Now we can check if the circle is smooth.
If you need to modify it.
Just use the edit board tool.
To adjust it.
If you want to move one curve point.
Just switch to the edit curve point tool.
To move one curve point.
And adjust it.
Next, let's check the adhesion of the side of the sewing line.
Repeat the copy function.
The connection of the sewing line.
Should be at a 90 degree angle.
So I add a curve point on both sides.
Then use the edit curve point tool.
To move it close to 90 degrees.
Then adjust the whole sewing line.
And adjust it.
The next step is,
Check the adhesion of the bottom of the sewing line.
If you feel the adhesion is not good.
Just remove the fold line.
And adjust it.
If there is no problem.
Let's see the adhesion of the bottom of the sewing line.
First we can see that.
The adhesion points are different.
Because the seam is too short.
Then we must to extend the seam.
After the extension, we use the edit tool to move the angle of its contact to close to 90 degrees.
Since we have just adjusted the length of the pre-central shape, we will also adjust the length of the pre-central shape on the previous line.
After adjusting the length of the pre-central shape, we can change the center of the pre-central shape to the free-line point.
Press the V key to show all the free-line points.
We see that there are three free-line points.
We move the center of the pre-central shape down to make the transition more natural.
The angle of the two free-line points will be adjusted to close to 90 degrees.
Press the V key to change the pre-central shape to 0 degrees.
Press the V key to adjust the length of the pre-central shape to 90 degrees.
For the free-line points, we press the V key to adjust the length of both sides.
Press the V key to adjust the length of the pre-central shape to no longer have a straight line.
Now we put the board back in place at the 2D window, select the board and right-click to rotate the X axis, then click on the horizontal line of the board, so that the board can be set up again.
Next, let's add the cutout. Let's start with the shoulder. Let's measure the length of the back piece from the height of the shoulder to the length of the shoulder.
In the 2D tool bar, select the cutout tool, then right-click on the shoulder of the front piece, enter the size and click OK.
We can see that the length of the other part of the front piece of the shoulder line is 2D.
We can see that the other part of the front piece of the shoulder line is 2D.
The length of the shoulder line of the back piece is 2.305.
Use the edit tool to right-click on the line to change the length.
Enter the value of the front piece, 2.311.
Click OK and then you can make changes.
Click OK to make changes.
Now we do the same thing on the side.
Right-click on the tool and click OK after entering the value.
Then check the length of the other section.
At this time, we will modify the side of the front piece.
Enter the same value as the back piece and click OK.
This completes the detailed modification of the top version.
Next, let's make a sleeve pattern.
Create a curve.
The widest part of the curve is 6.25 inches.
The longest part is 22 inches.
Next, mark the 6-inch height of the sleeve with the internal line tool.
Change to the plus point line tool.
We mark the width of the sleeve as 4 inches.
Then use the internal multiline tool to show the outline of the sleeve.
Then make the sleeve 3.
We give Ability 1 a times .
We この将等分点向45°方向移動0.5英寸一點 resemb égal
Next, use the decimal dot to change the curve of the sleeve pattern.
迴構倍測
And use to limit the无线溜度
Use the soon for button.
Select the outer descriptive line of the sleeve.
And flop the right button.
Right-click and select the version.
We will select half of the version.
Then we will use the edit version tool.
Click on the center line of the number.
Right-click and align the edit seam line.
Now when we select the point of the frame line outside the tree, there will be a handle.
We can move the handle to adjust the angle again.
Since the previous version was aligned with the edit,
there will be a link between the two sides.
After the adjustment, we will re-evaluate the outline of the sleeve.
Then check the size of the sleeve.
The difference here is very small, so we will not change it.
Now we will right-click on the sleeve version and remove the link.
And move the point of the sleeve line to the point of the curve.
We can use the comparison version length tool to add a cutout for our sleeve.
Due to the point of the inner line of the version is covered by the point of the outline of the version,
So at this time,
we need to convert the inner line of the version to the base line.
Here you can adjust the position of the shoulder line.
The tool used is the edit version tool.
It can select points and select lines.
Now we select the inner line of the front, sleeve and back.
Press Shift to select more, then right-click and convert to the base line.
So when I use the comparison version length tool again, it is effective.
Then we first click on the point of the bottom of the sleeve.
Then click on the point under the sleeve.
When we move the mouse, the plate will move along the edge.
Now we right-click on the mouse in the front space.
The first option in the box, the moving plate, is for adding a cutout on the sleeve.
The fixed plate is for adding a cutout on the sleeve.
Here we choose the two-sided plate, which can be added a cutout on the sleeve and the sleeve at the same time.
Move forward to the point of the shoulder line.
Here we choose the moving plate.
Please add a cutout on the sleeve.
Switch to the edit version tool to position the sleeve.
Now we do the same operation in the back.
Add a cutout at the focal point of the back of the big body and the sleeve.
Use the cutout tool to add a cutout at the midpoint of the sleeve.
Adjust the fence and the length of the sleeve.
premade the leather until its long and mid-length.
Adjust the back of the climb by moving the knife tror we called the cutout.
And then go to 3D window 10 million.
First, last the stiffen the sleeve.
Open the制 opt point, and put the sleeve on this degree.
The sleeve is require feature to be voiced on the cover of the cloth happening here.
Here, we can also use the automatic sewing tool to arrange our sewing line.
After arranging, confirm the sewing line, and then turn on the simulation.
The sleeve is finished.
Now we will display the basic line on the clothing.
We will change the position of the virtual model to put it down with both hands.
We can use the pose file clip in the picture window.
However, in order to prevent the virtual model and the clothing from colliding at the bottom,
we can open the X-Ray combination and manually adjust the model's posture.
Click on the joint point and a positional ball will pop up.
On the upper right corner of this positional ball, there will be a small virtual model.
Clicking on this small virtual model means that we are adjusting the corresponding posture at the same time.
After the adjustment is complete, turn off the X-Ray.
The shortcut key is Shift X.
Finally, we can remove the tape on the model.
We choose the Edit Measure tool.
Click on the mark line drawn on the model's shoulder before.
Then click on the right button to delete the size.
In order to see the result more effectively,
we can increase the quality of the clothing.
After that, we can start the simulation.
Then the commercial basic model is completed.
The next stage is the combination model .
You can adjust it according to your own size table.
Thank you for watching.
I hope this video can help you to improve the operation of 2D tablet in CLOVE.